<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>NOVA Python</title><link href="http://novapython.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://novapython.org/feeds/Meetups.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://novapython.org/</id><updated>2012-07-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Novapy in July</title><link href="http://novapython.org/novapy-in-july.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-07-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Day</name></author><id>tag:novapython.org,2012-07-21:novapy-in-july.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Another entry in what is apparently an uninterrupted string of Novapy event updates!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://twitter.com/#!/gekitsuu"&gt;&amp;#64;gekitsuu&lt;/a&gt; spoke about Rackspace and Python and Zombies. He covered Python integration with libcloud and MongoDB and how to work that into a Rackspace deployment. We all learned a little bit and had a lot of new faces in the crowd as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I announced the Dgentle Django class this August as well. The class sold out before midnight! It will be an amazing time I’m sure. We are finalizing the last details now, and will be updating everyone along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="meetup"></category><category term="paas"></category><category term="rackspace"></category><category term="zombies"></category></entry><entry><title>June Nova Python Meetup</title><link href="http://novapython.org/june-nova-python-meetup.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-06-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Day</name></author><id>tag:novapython.org,2012-06-22:june-nova-python-meetup.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Less than 24 hours after the meetup I’ve got my code deploying to The Cloud!
Of course, my code is written in PHP, and my cloud is based on Rackspace...
so I strayed a little bit from &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.redmonocle.com/"&gt;Jen Rullmann's&lt;/a&gt; presentation, but its the thought that counts. The workshop last night went very well. We had several linux users, the ever growing Mac contingent was there, and we had Windows users as well. Yet, we still managed to get virtualenv and Django running locally on everyone’s system, and then pushed to EC2 using a Fabric config file. That is the same fabfile I modified to get my PHP code up and running on Rackspace. Fabric is pretty great and Jen’s example cut out a lot of tedious steps to learn the ins and outs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a strong turnout. Deploying applications reliably across systems is a hot topic. It doesn’t matter if its AWS, VMware, Heroku or Rackspace, it seems to be what everyone wants to do. Getting a hands on tutorial was strong step in the right direction. Next we could delve into Fabric more. Explore more of the AWS services, hear from some of the other providers out there as well…. So until that next time..&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="meetup"></category><category term="paas"></category><category term="aws"></category><category term="zombies"></category></entry></feed>