<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>NOVA Python</title><link href="http://blog.novapython.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.novapython.org/feeds/Workshops.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.novapython.org/</id><updated>2012-08-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Djentle Django Followup</title><link href="http://blog.novapython.org/djentle-django-followup.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-08-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Day</name></author><id>tag:blog.novapython.org,2012-08-15:djentle-django-followup.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Novapython's first Djentle Django workshop has been a great success. Thanks
goes out to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://nvcc.edu"&gt;NVCC&lt;/a&gt; for providing the space and equipment. Also thanks to
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://willowtreeapps.com"&gt;Willow Tree Apps&lt;/a&gt; for providing two days of lunch for everyone. Also, we
should mention all the teachers and helpers that made this possible:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alan Elkner (aelkner .at. elkner.net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Annalee Flower Horne&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eddie Welker (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://twitter.com/edwelker/"&gt;&amp;#64;edwelker&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jackie Kazil (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/JackieKazil"&gt;&amp;#64;JackieKazi&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jeff Elkner (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://elkner.net/"&gt;elkner.net&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jen Rullmann (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/RedMonocle"&gt;&amp;#64;RedMonocle&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kevin Cole (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/ubuntourist"&gt;&amp;#64;ubuntourist&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mackenzie Morgan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matt Makai (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://twitter.com/makaimc/"&gt;&amp;#64;makaimc&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ryan Day (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/RyanDay2"&gt;&amp;#64;RyanDay2&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="class" src="images/class.jpg" /&gt; &lt;img alt="helpers" src="images/action.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we've competed this class, it's a good time to time to look over what
worked, what didn't, what to add/remove, and just think about stuff in general.
What better way than to go through the questions I sent out to all the attendees&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="preworkshop"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Preworkshop&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked the following questions of &lt;strong&gt;23&lt;/strong&gt; attendees, and received &lt;strong&gt;12&lt;/strong&gt; responses:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How did you hear about this workshop? &lt;em&gt;(Pyladies / Novapython / NVCC)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; Pyladies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9&lt;/strong&gt; Novapython&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt; NVCC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt; One attendee checked both Pyladies and Novapython&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is your current comfort level with HTML/CSS? &lt;em&gt;(Very Comfortable / Comfortable / No Opinion / Not So Comfortable)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; Very Comfortable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; Comfortable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; No Opinion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; Not So Comfortable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is your current comfort level with Python? &lt;em&gt;(Very Comfortable / Comfortable / No Opinion / Not So Comfortable)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; Very Comfortable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt; Comfortable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; No Opinion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;0&lt;/strong&gt; Not So Comfortable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is your current comfort level with Django? &lt;em&gt;(Very Comfortable / Comfortable / No Opinion / Not So Comfortable)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;0&lt;/strong&gt; Very Comfortable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;0&lt;/strong&gt; Comfortable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; No Opinion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt; Not So Comfortable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have you used any other web frameworks / programming languages? &lt;em&gt;(Open Ended)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are there any specific topics you would like covered? &lt;em&gt;(Open Ended)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Was there anything special about this workshop that made you want to sign up? &lt;em&gt;(Open Ended)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are your biggest worries about taking this workshop? &lt;em&gt;(Open Ended)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="preworkshop-results"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Preworkshop Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what we were hoping for! Now, if everyone had completed the survey, then
the results would have been a little different, but not by much. We had some
true beginners, but nobody had the fear. The opended questions are a little
harder to quantify, but the &lt;em&gt;majority of attendees were worried about being
left behind&lt;/em&gt;. After going through the postworkshop results, I feel we did a
great job in alleviating this worry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, an informal survey of the class showed a lot of programming experience in
other languages and frameworks. Java was prevelant. I had a lot of side
questions about Flask and Pyramid as well. A good bit of the class had database
experience (odd, if you ask me. I would have thought more HTML than databases).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="postworkshop"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Postworkshop&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We received only &lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; responses for the postworkshop, which tells me we need a
better way of gathering the results. But anyway, the questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is your current comfort level with HTML/CSS? &lt;em&gt;(Very Comfortable / Comfortable / No Opinion / Not So Comfortable)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; Very Comfortable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; Comfortable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;0&lt;/strong&gt; No Opinion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;0&lt;/strong&gt; Not So Comfortable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is your current comfort level with Python? &lt;em&gt;(Very Comfortable / Comfortable / No Opinion / Not So Comfortable)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt; Very Comfortable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; Comfortable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;0&lt;/strong&gt; No Opinion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt; Not So Comfortable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is your current comfort level with Django? &lt;em&gt;(Very Comfortable / Comfortable / No Opinion / Not So Comfortable)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;0&lt;/strong&gt; Very Comfortable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; Comfortable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt; No Opinion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;0&lt;/strong&gt; Not So Comfortable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What topics would you have liked to learn more about? &lt;em&gt;(Open Ended)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What was the least helpful part of this course? &lt;em&gt;(Open Ended)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does anything particularly interesting stand out in your memory? &lt;em&gt;(Open Ended)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Would you be interested in a followup course? &lt;em&gt;(Boolean)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Had you ever used Linux before this course? &lt;em&gt;(Boolean)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did you feel rushed and/or overwhelmed during this course? &lt;em&gt;(Boolean)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; No&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="postworkshop-results"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Postworkshop Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Success! The &amp;quot;No So Comfortable&amp;quot; Django responses went to 0, and the
comfortable responses went up. Nobody reported feeling rushed or overwhelmed in
the process. I also see that everyone who responded had used linux in the past,
and I know this wasn't the case when we were helping out attendees. So this
whole thing probably suffers a little bias.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But! Everyone seemed to have a good time, learn a little something, and not
get intimidated or feel uncomfortable. Those are the results we really cared
about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="next-steps"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Next Steps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the next course, we need to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do a better job of surveying the class. More results will help us improve.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find a way to break up instruction/coding into more distinct segments to reduce downtime and crosstalk which may get confusing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the more complete survey results effectively in order to cover desired topics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build a better interface for the course that attendees can reference (think website with tutorials and links all in one package)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks again to all the teachers and sponsors!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="meta"></category></entry><entry><title>Djentle Django Day 2</title><link href="http://blog.novapython.org/djentle-django-day-2.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-08-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Day</name></author><id>tag:blog.novapython.org,2012-08-12:djentle-django-day-2.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The first workshop has been completed successfully. Thanks to a great team,
participants were able to build a working Django web site from nothing.
Some participants were brand new to Linux as well. So there was alot of ground
covered. Fortunately, Django is straight forward and pretty easy to work with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Huge thanks to the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://nvcc.edu"&gt;Northen Virginia Community College&lt;/a&gt; for providing a lab outfitted with computers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.willowtreeapps.com/"&gt;Willow Tree Apps&lt;/a&gt; provided lunch on both days of the workshop, allowing us to interact with eachother and learn that much more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And of course, those who taught us all something new&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alan Elkner (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://elkner.net/"&gt;elkner.net&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Annalee Flower Horne (how does one reach you?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eddie Welker (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://twitter.com/edwelker/"&gt;&amp;#64;edwelker&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jackie Kazil (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/JackieKazil"&gt;&amp;#64;JackieKazi&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jeff Elkner (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://elkner.net/"&gt;elkner.net&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jen Rullmann (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/RedMonocle"&gt;&amp;#64;RedMonocle&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kevin Cole (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/ubuntourist"&gt;&amp;#64;ubuntourist&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matt Makai (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://twitter.com/makaimc/"&gt;&amp;#64;makaimc&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ryan Day (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/RyanDay2"&gt;&amp;#64;RyanDay2&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a lot of data and thoughts and ideas, but I have to compile it all first.
I hope to put up something graphing the spreadsheet data and ideas later this
week. So check back!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until then, quote of the course, &amp;quot;Most of computer programming is just doing math the wrong way&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="meta"></category></entry><entry><title>Djentle Django Day 1</title><link href="http://blog.novapython.org/djentle-django-day-1.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-08-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Day</name></author><id>tag:blog.novapython.org,2012-08-11:djentle-django-day-1.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Day #1 of Djentle Django is complete. We did seriously well. Our class has a very diverse range of skills. There are some who are installing their favorite IDE and running through the Django tutorial. There are a couple who have not used a command line before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even those with no linux experience were looking at DEBUG dumps, and finding the problem in their code. Fixing the problem, then restarting the Django server. Thats pretty good. The amount of knowledge required to bring up a Django web site is pretty astronomical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yes!&lt;/strong&gt; It really is when you think about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the push to teach everyone to code, you have to look at exactly what it takes to code. You have to have a text editor. Ubuntu doesn't have gedit on the standard toolbar. So just open a terminal and run gedit. But how do you know gedit exists? What are you even editing? Oh you should run django-admin.py? Whats a terminal?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today's biggest issues:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Editing the text, by far. Moving from text editor to command line was time consuming and complex for those who had never done it before. This is where I would focus most of the setup time. An editor that autocompletes Python code, and can highlight syntax errors as you code. However! I have been told that these IDEs (Eclipse, looking at you) are pretty easy to &amp;quot;accidentally&amp;quot; break. Somebody changes a setting somewhere, and now you are out 10 minutes trying to figrue out what went wrong. Also, how does the student simulate that environment when they get back home? How do you load a virtualenv into the Eclipse configs, when you are just barely understanding what a virtualenv even is? You know what always works though? Vim :) &amp;lt;esc&amp;gt;i just keep typing&amp;lt;esc&amp;gt;:wq. And it works when you get home as well. You don't need to master anything. If something is weird, &amp;lt;esc&amp;gt;i. And you're back.... just a thought.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Typos. This could be addressed by the IDE though. Highlight unknown variables. This would save a LOT of time, trying code paths until you hit that one typo, and then have to navigate your way back to that file. If you don't do this everyday, this is time consuming and frustrating.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we need a better editor. I think that would increase enjoyment. I'll have to wait for the post-workshop surveys to come back as well though.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="meta"></category></entry><entry><title>Workshop Meeting #1</title><link href="http://blog.novapython.org/workshop-meeting-1.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-08-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Day</name></author><id>tag:blog.novapython.org,2012-08-08:workshop-meeting-1.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just finished a workshop related lunch with &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.mattmakai.com/"&gt;Matt Makai&lt;/a&gt;. Things are looking
up and our plan is solid. We will have some pretty sleek presentations
for our information as well. We discussed several things, most notably:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Static sites&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Github pages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Common pitfalls of programming tutorials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dgentle Django's huge traction is getting us tens of views every single day,
so we need to make sure that the site is responsive. Item #1 leads to #2,
which is obviously the reason I am writing all this up. I just had to try out
Github pages. I am very pleased. I would like some ideas on themes for pelican,
but that will come soon enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So on to the real meat, #3. We plan on starting out simple. The what and
why of web frameworks in general. This is necessary because Django is a
pretty large undertaking for a simple website. So you need to know why you
would choose Djhango in the first place. Knowing why will make all the
abstractions (MVC) make sense, instead of seeming like a hurdle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, Matt and I were discussing the two types of programming instruction:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How install X and create a &amp;quot;Hello World&amp;quot; app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Theory behind distributed credit card chargebacks when your backup ESB is on the fritz.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a little bit of knowledge inbetween those two situations that is
rarely discussed. But the vast majority of people fall in between those two
scenarios. How do you reach them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So. I don't know. But, I figure it's a good enough question to justify
throwing together a Github Pages account with a little bit of content.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="meta"></category></entry></feed>